NWANOCHIRI PAUL

Address: Block 2, flat 28 Bonny Cantonment, Victoria Island. Lagos

Telephone: 07067206753, 09053448827 Email: Nwanochiripaul@yahoo.com About Me: About.me/paulnwanochiri

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/paul-nwanochiri Twitter: @paulpeters992

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Cloud Support Engineer with over 5 years of experience in the IT industry. Proven ability to provide exceptional customer service and technical support to Enterprise-level clients. Specializes in cloud-based solutions, including Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Microsoft Azure.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Azure Administration Associate
- Microsoft Azure Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals.
- Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified Trainer
- Certificate in Data Analysis (Radius Institute of Technology)

WORK EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER (L2) | TEK EXPERTS NIG. LTD

Jul. 2021 – Present

Yesuf Abila Abiodun Oniru Road, Maroko 106104, Lagos.

- Develop and implement the most common re-pro cases to identify potential software defects, misconfiguration of issues in the client's environment.
- Deploying and managing Azure resources while leveraging automation pipeline for fast paced robust application development environment
- Help in migration of resources from the on premises or other cloud platform to the public cloud and viceversa.
- Troubleshoot issues relating to Linux server distributions (RHEL, Ubuntu, CentOS).
- Setup re-pros on Azure Git, merging code from develop branch to master branch and make it ready for deployment.
- Automate Network Configuration changes like NSG rule updates and Load Balancing rule changes while leveraging Terra-form and Azure DevOps.
- Deployed Infrastructure into Azure using Power-Shell, Azure CLI and ARM.
- Built and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into micro services, improving developer workflow,

- Automated infrastructure provisioning on Azure using Terra-form and Ansible.
- Push codes through GIT version control and build jobs with continuous integration tool Travis CI
- Knowledge of networking concepts (e.g., DNS, TCP/IP, DNS, VNET Peering, OSI and firewalls)
- Assist with managing, maintaining, monitoring, and securing (including data security) of all servers including installations, upgrades, patches, and documentation.
- Deploy azure resources using Azure ARM deployments / Automation /Azure CLI / Power-Shell / DSC / Bash
- Experience with container-based deployments using Docker, working with Docker images, Docker Hub and Docker-registries and Kubernetes.
- Setup repos on Azure Git, merging code from develop branch to master branch and make it ready for deployment.
- Automate Network Configuration changes like NSG rule updates and Load Balancing rule changes while leveraging Terraform and Azure DevOps.

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER | F6 SOFTWARE

Apr 2019 – June 2021

- Created templates and clone servers in VMware and Virtual Box environments. · Produced, enhanced, and executed the deployment of automated tools to increase efficiencies across the organization.
- Design and implement architectural requirements, system specifications, input/output processes and parameters for software integration.
- Conduct integration, test, bug fixes, and other software maintenance activities. · Created and employing disaster recovery solutions and assisting with continuous improvement activities.
- Worked on racking and stacking On-Premise and Cloud servers for infrastructure project at Datacenter.
- Managed the IAM role and policies for users within the environment for access to the cloud infrastructure.
- Efficiently collaborated within and across agile teams to maximize productivity.
- Supporting software development and data management projects that prepare large datasets for delivery to a shared computing environment.

IT ADMINISTRATOR | PRINCE EBEANO SUPERMARKET

Nov. 2018- Jun. 2019

Chevron Road, Lekki Phase. Lagos

- Managed the company's cloud-based ERP to track business resources cash, raw materials, and productions
- User administration (setup and maintaining account) on Windows and Linux environment
- Maintaining system in the active directory and passing group policies
- Quickly arrange repair for hardware in occasion of hardware failure
- Monitor system performance and draw action plan to optimize performance
- Create file systems in windows and Linux servers and broadcast this to servers in the same VLAN and domains
- Install software and monitor security vulnerabilities

Create a backup and recovery policy in case of disasters

IT TECHNICAL SUPPORT INTERN | BEDGE ACADEMY

Baderinwa Alabi Street, Lekki. Lagos.

- Trained as an IT intern in the technical support team.
- Assisted the IT team in the maintenance of hardware, software, and other operations.
- Conduct troubleshot issues with equipment like printers, computers, and servers.
- Performed repairs and software updates installations on devices.
- Gained knowledge on web development, Desktop publishing and IT networking.
- Carried out Personal research and constantly seek to update my technical knowledge in IT support.

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma: Chemical Engineering
 Imo State Polytechnic – Ohaji LGA
National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)
Oct. 2018

CORE COMPETENCE

- Proficiency in Microsoft Office suite: Word, Excel, PowerPoint &Access
- Good verbal and written professional communication, fluent in English.
- Passion for providing exemplary customer service, strong customer focus.
- Programming/scripting experience (Bash, JavaScript, Json, PowerShell)
- Able to work effectively at all levels in an organization. Excellent active listening skills.
- Working technical knowledge of Microsoft Azure and AWS cloud platform and operations.
- Knowledgeable in computer operating systems; Hardware and software
- Strong understanding of Monitoring and Troubleshooting tools (ASC, Quick- assist, CMAT, Javis, Azure Guide and AVD)

INTERESTS

- Graphics Design
- Reading and Researching
- Forex Trading
- Football
- Meeting new people

REFERENCE

Available upon request

Nov. 2018- Jun. 2019